Jack Crawford Robertson

Contact Information:

Email: jack@ya-ya.co.uk Phone: 07588502199

Website: jack-robertson.co.uk

Portfolio: <u>written.jack-robertson.co.uk</u> Project: <u>maya.jack-robertson.co.uk</u>

About Me:

I am a communicator specialising in data-driven storytelling and visual communication. My expertise lies in blending powerful storytelling, data analytics, and engaging visual narratives with effective messaging to simplify complex topics such as climate change, geopolitics, and social sciences. I excel in creating accessible and visually compelling data visualisations using modern web technologies to inspire empathetic understanding.

Education:

The Royal College of Art

MA Digital Direction, Archived, 2023 - 2024

 Developed "Maya," a tool for Middle East based NGOs to interpret complex data, utilising advanced data visualisation techniques and web-based technologies such as Next.js and D3.

Central Saint Martins

BA Communication Design, 1st Honours, 2019 - 2022

• Specialised in communication design with a focus on data visualisation and user experience design.

Experience:

Data Journalist

July 2024 - Present | ICE-HUB

- Lead the development of new data storytelling methods for corporate events.
- Produced a industry first web-based interactive research project, developed using Next.js and D3.

Digital Consultant

July 2023 - Present | UK Pollster, UK Water Supplier and the NHS

- Consulted leading UK pollster to design web-based interactive visualisations using React, D3, and TypeScript, making complex polling data accessible.
- Advised one of the UK's largest water suppliers on integrating AI process to automate, and improve financial workflows.
- Developed automated workflows using Python and JavaScript for the NHS, resulting in improved cross-team understanding within the mental health system.

Data-Driven Designer - Girardot

September 2022 - 2023

- Delivered data-driven advertising and visual content for multiple Global Equity Income Funds, utilising data visualisation tools like Excel, Plotly, and Adobe Creative Cloud to increase their value by over 180%.
- Produced weekly editorial content for The Times, The Week, The Spectator and Condé Nast, honing skills in rapid content production and storytelling.

Event Production - Capgemini Invent

July 2020 - 2021

- Worked with The Faculty on a major Capgemini event in Paris, assisting in event execution and visual design.
- Created iconography and visual assets using Adobe Illustrator and After Effects to enhance the event's visual appeal.

Skills:

- Data Visualisation: React, D3, ObservablePlot, Plotly, ChartJS
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, JavaScript, Next.js
- Mapping Technologies: MapLibre, DeckGL, Leaflet, Mapbox
- Data Management & Analysis: Python, Excel
- Design & Visual Communication: Adobe Illustrator, After Effects
- **Project Management:** Agile methodologies, workshop facilitation

Achievements:

- Complexity & Design Award at Central Saint Martins.
- Developed "Maya," an online policy tool aiding NGOs in the MENA region, recognised for its innovative use of data visualisation to secure funding from international donors.